<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Krish Patel</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Krish Patel</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Students Should Turn Off ChatGPT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-crutch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-crutch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transcribed from a voice memo, this post examines the risks of relying on AI tools like ChatGPT in education, particularly for novice computer science students, and advocates for learning fundamentals without technological crutches.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflections-on-ai-in-education&#34;&gt;Reflections on AI in Education&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been considering the role of artificial intelligence in educational settings, specifically the unrestricted use of tools such as ChatGPT, Gemini, or Cursor at the college, high school, or middle school levels. This discussion focuses not on assistive tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flintk12.com/&#34;&gt;Flint&lt;/a&gt;, which are controlled by educators, but on freely available independent AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an incoming Member of Technical Staff at &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.ai&#34;&gt;xAI&lt;/a&gt;, where I&amp;rsquo;ll be developing and deploying secure AI solutions for federal partners. Previously, I was at &lt;a href=&#34;https://palantir.com&#34;&gt;Palantir Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, where I engineered GEOINT exploitation applications for national security workflows. I&amp;rsquo;ve also conducted quantum research at &lt;a href=&#34;https://orise.orau.gov&#34;&gt;Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education&lt;/a&gt;, worked on cryptographic optimization at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nsa.gov&#34;&gt;National Security Agency&lt;/a&gt;, and developed bioinformatics algorithms at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ncsu.edu&#34;&gt;North Carolina State University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pursuing an accelerated Bachelors and Masters of Computer Science at North Carolina State University as a Park Scholar, with a focus on quantum computing, cryptography, and applied AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Zero Cost Schooling Builds Purpose</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/risk-capital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/risk-capital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While originaly written as a letter to the Friends of Park Scholarships, this reflection explores how programs that eliminate our &lt;strong&gt;relative&lt;/strong&gt; educational costs fundamentally transform our ability to take risks and pursue meaningful work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hidden-value-risk-capital&#34;&gt;The Hidden Value: Risk Capital&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is Krish, and I am a Park Scholar in the Class of 2026. While the opportunities this prestigious program has provided have been life-changing in many ways, I want to share a perspective that often goes undiscussed: how programs that drive the cost of attendance down to zero or close to it fundamentally transform our ability to take risks and pursue meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
